Guide to the Whitney Humanities Center, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Whitney Humanities Center, Yale University, records
1951-1987
RU 569
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
27.5
(24 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, student files, senior essays, and subject and administrative files documenting the operations of the Whitney Humanities Center. Topics include the Humanities Advisory Committee, the A. Whitney Griswold Faculty Research Fund, the Frederick W. Hilles Publication Fund, the National Institute for the Humanities, the Scholar of the House program, and the center's undergraduate programs.
Whitney Humanities Center
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 37 (YRG 37), Records of associations, institutes, centers, and organizations affiliated with Yale University.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Biographical / Historical
The Whitney Humanities Center was established in 1981 as an interdisciplinary institution "designed to enable and enhance research, thinking, and scholarly exchange in all fields of the humanities and throughout [Yale] University."
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, student files, senior essays, and subject and administrative files documenting the operations of the Whitney Humanities Center. Topics include the Humanities Advisory Committee, the A. Whitney Griswold Faculty Research Fund, the Frederick W. Hilles Publication Fund, the National Institute for the Humanities, the Scholar of the House program, and the center's undergraduate programs.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Humanities -- Study and teaching; Research institutes; Whitney Humanities Center
- Records, 1972-1978; Accession 1983-A-008
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Humanities Advisory Committee
    - Special Programs, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Evaluation Procedures, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Giamatti and Spence, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Afro-American Studies, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Classics Department, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Comparative Literature Department, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - French Department, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - English Department, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - German Department, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - History of Art Department, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Honorary Degree, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Italian Department, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Ltnguistics Department, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Near Eastern Languages, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Minutes and Agenda, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - American Studies Department, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Religious Studies Department, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Spanish Languages Department, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - East Asian Languages, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Child Study Center, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - History Department, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Music Department, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Philosophy, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Slavic Languages, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Spanish and Portuguese, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Mellon Center, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Special Courses in the Humanities, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Provost Moderations, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Programs, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - University Council Report, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Theater Studies, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Minutes and Agenda, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - American Studies Department, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Classics Department, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Comparative Literature, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - English Department, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - East Asian Department, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - French Department, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - History Department, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - History of Art Department, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - History of Science and Medicine, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Italian Department, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Linguistics Department, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Medieval Studies, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Music Department, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Near Estern Languages Department, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Philosophy Department, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Religious Studies Department, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Slavic Languages Department, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Spanish Languages, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Council for Comparative Study of Culture and Society, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Report to Review Status of Minority Students, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Tenure Positions -Humanities, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Departmental Secretary, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Committee on Summer Programs, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Humanities Division Budget, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Humanities Division Budget, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Yale College, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Division of Humanities -Information, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Senior Appointments Committee, 1976-1976 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Division of Humanities: Request for Information, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Approved Summer Programs and Conferences, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Humanities Seminars, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Yale College Council, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - American Studies Department, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Classics Department, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Classics and Philosophy, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Comparative Literature, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - East Asian Languages, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - English Department, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - French Department, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - German Department, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - History Department, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - History of Art Department (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - History of Science and Medicine, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - Italian Department, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Linguistics Department, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Medieval Studies, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Music Department, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Near Eastern Languages, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Philosophy Department, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Religious Studies Department, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Slavic Languages, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Spanish Languages, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Language Survey, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Modern Era, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Ph.D. Program in Romance Philosophy, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Planning Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - Humanities Advisory Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Agenda and Minutes, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Humanities Advisory Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Enrollments, 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Tenure Positions, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Affirmative Action, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Literature Proposal, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Inter-Office Correspondence (Sent), 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Inter-Office Correspondence (Received), 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - Affirmative Action Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - Jean Gauden (Film Proposal), 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - University Council Visiting Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - Graduate School Dean's Report, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - Special Reports, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 103)
    - Renaissance Study Proposal: Doctoral Program, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - Panorama for Humanities Department, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Director of Members, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - French Department, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Linguistics Department, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Budget: Division of Humanities, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Budget: Division of Humanities, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Department Secretary, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - Classics Department, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - British Art Center, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - Visiting Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Provost's Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Romance Languages: Considerations, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Priorities for the Humanities, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Rothenberg Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Danforth Proposal, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Notes and Records of Meetings, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - Capital Campaign Fund, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - Humanities Prospectuses, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Sterling Memorial Library, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - New Graduate Programs, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 124)
    - General Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 125)
    - Summer Term, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 126)
    - American Studies: Considerations, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 127)
    - Classics Department: Considerations, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 128)
    - English Department: Considerations, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 129)
    - German Department, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 130)
    - German Department: Considerations, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 131)
    - History Department, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 132)
    - History Department: Considerations, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 133)
    - History of Art: Considerations, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 134)
    - Linguistic Department: Considerations, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 135)
    - Mellon Center, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 136)
    - Music Department: Considerations, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 137)
    - Near Eastern Department: Considerations, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 138)
    - Philosophy Department: Considerations, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 139)
    - Religious Studies: Considerations, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 140)
    - Division of Humanities; Budget, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 141)
    - Division of Humanities: Budget Deferred Account, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 142)
    - Division of Humanities: Budget: Ronald Jager's Salary (Box 2, Folder 143)
    - Proposals: Humanities Institute, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 144)
    - Notes of Records and Meetings, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 145)
    - Romance Languages, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 146)
    - American Studies: Considerations, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 147)
    - Classics Department: Considerations, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 148)
    - English Department: Considerations, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 149)
    - History Department Considerations, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 150)
    - History of Art: Considerations, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 151)
    - Linguistics Department: Considerations, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 152)
    - Music Department: Considerations, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 153)
    - Near Eastern Department: Considrations, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 154)
    - Philosophy Department: Considerations, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 155)
    - Religious Studies: Considerations, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 156)
    - Romance Languages: Considerations, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 157)
  - A. Whitney Griswold Research Fund and Hilles Publication Fund
    - Hilles Applications (May 1977), 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 158)
    - Hilles Applications (Nov 1977, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 159)
    - Hilles Applications (Feb 1978), 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 160)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 161)
    - Griswold Awards (Apr 1978), 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 162)
    - Griswold Applications (Apr 1978), 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 163)
    - Griswold Awards (Feb 1978), 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 164)
    - Griswold Applications (Feb 1978), 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 165)
    - Budget Sheets, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 166)
    - Griswold Awards, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 167)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 168)
    - Griswold Applications (Nov 1977), 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 169)
    - Griswold Applications (Apr 1977), 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 170)
    - Griswold Awards (Apr 1977), 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 171)
    - Griswold Applications (Feb 1977), 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 172)
    - Griswold Awards (Feb 1977), 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 173)
    - Griswold Applications (Nov 1975), 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 174)
    - Griswold Awards (Nov 1976), 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 175)
    - Griswold Budget Sheets, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 176)
    - Contingency Awards, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 177)
    - Grants Awarded, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 178)
    - Griswold Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 179)
    - Griswold Award Recipients (April 1976), 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 180)
    - Whiting Fellowship Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 181)
    - Griswold Fund Applications (Apr 1, 1976), 1978 (Box 3, Folder 182)
    - Griswold Award Recipients (Feb 1976, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 183)
    - Griswold Fund Applications (Feb 1976), 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 184)
    - Griswold Award Recipients, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 185)
    - Griswold Fund Applications (Nov 1975), 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 186)
    - Grants Awarded, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 187)
    - Griswold Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 188)
    - A. Whitney Griswold Awards
      - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 189)
      - Abstracts: Apr 1975, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 190)
      - Action taken Apr 1975, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 191)
      - Applications to fund, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 192)
      - Action taken, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 193)
      - Applications to fund, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 194)
      - Action taken, Nov 1,1974, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 195)
      - Applications for Nov 1, 1974, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 196)
    - A. Whitney Griswold Budget Records (500A-20-87173): Academic Year, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 197)
    - A. Whitney Griswold Awards, Apr, 1974, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 198)
    - A. Whitney Griswold Awards: Proposals, Apr, 1974, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 199)
    - A. Whitney Griswold: Taken, Feb 1974, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 200)
    - A. Whitney Griswold Awards: Proposals, Nov, 1973, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 201)
    - A. Whitney Griswold Awards Faculty Proposals, Feb, 1974, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 202)
    - A. Whitney Griswold Awards: Action Taken, Nov, 1973, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 203)
    - Council on Humanities Budget (568A-31-56048)
      - 1974 Apr-Jun, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 204)
      - Ongoing costs, daily expenditures, receipts, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 205)
      - 1974 Jan-Mar, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 206)
      - 26908, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 207)
      - 1973 Oct-Dec, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 208)
      - Academic Year 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 209)
    - Council on the Humanities, General
      - Press Releases, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 210)
      - Edwin McClellan, Chairman, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 211)
      - Directory of New Members, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 212)
      - Directory of New Members, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 213)
      - Appointment of Members, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 214)
      - Appointment of Members, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 215)
      - Council Agenda, 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 216)
      - Current Agenda and Notes, 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 217)
      - Memorandum, Agenda, Notes, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 218)
      - Council Agenda and Minutes, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 219)
      - Intra-Council correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 220)
      - Intra-Council correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 221)
      - General correspondence, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 222)
      - Subcommittee, Spring 1975, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 223)
      - The Second Culture and Language Program, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 224)
      - Vita of Planning Group, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 225)
      - Proposal for Establishment, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 226)
      - Proposal - General Planning, undated (Box 3, Folder 227)
  - Miscellaneous Files, 1973-1978
    - Provost Advisory Committee: needs of the Science Departments, undated (Box 3, Folder 228)
    - Psychoanalytic Studies on the Humanities: General correspondence (Box 3, Folder 229)
    - Psychoanalytic Studies Center Proposal: correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 230)
    - Library Acquisitions: Academic Year, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 231)
    - Miller Notes: Spring 1973 (Box 3, Folder 232)
    - National Institute for the Humanities
      - Professor Lamar no date, 0 (Box 4, Folder 233)
      - Selection Committee Chairman: Giamatti, 0 (Box 4, Folder 234)
      - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 235)
      - Executive Board, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 236)
      - G. Hartman, undated (Box 4, Folder 237)
      - National Humanities Institute at Yale, undated (Box 4, Folder 238)
      - Executive Board, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 239)
      - National Humanities Institute, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 240)
      - Committee on the Future, undated (Box 4, Folder 241)
      - Panel: Humanities Today, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 242)
      - Trinity Parish House space, undated (Box 4, Folder 243)
      - Yale Documents, 1973 - (Box 4, Folder 244)
      - Rosenblatt Letter, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 245)
      - Senior Fellow Suggestions, n. d. (Box 4, Folder 246)
      - General correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 247)
      - NEH Response to Proposal, undated (Box 4, Folder 248)
      - Nominations for NHI Executive Committee, n. d. (Box 4, Folder 249)
      - National Humanities Center: Proposed Draft, undated (Box 4, Folder 250)
      - The Modern University: Project for National Endowment for the Humanities, undated (Box 4, Folder 251)
      - National Endowment for the Humanities: General Information, undated (Box 4, Folder 252)
      - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 253)
      - Summary of Proposal Grant, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 254)
      - Curriculum Proposals, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 255)
      - National Institute for Humanities at Yale, undated (Box 4, Folder 256)
      - National Endowment for the Humanities, undated (Box 4, Folder 257)
      - Executive Board, undated (Box 4, Folder 258)
      - National Endowment for the Humanities: Pilot Grant Proposal, undated (Box 4, Folder 259)
      - National Endowment for the Humanities, undated (Box 4, Folder 260)
      - Provost's Advisory Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 261)
      - Campaign for Yale and the Humanities, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 262)
      - Division of Humanities and Campaign, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 263)
      - Jay Warner, undated (Box 4, Folder 264)
      - Provost's Advisory Committee: Humanities, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 265-266)
      - The Paul Mellon Center, undated (Box 4, Folder 267)
      - Interdisciplinary and Humanities Programs (Box 4, Folder 268)
      - Yale Proposal, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 269)
      - NEH Summer Seminars, undated (Box 4, Folder 270)
      - National Endowment for the Humanities: Report on Special Projects Program, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 271)
      - Brochure, undated (Box 4, Folder 272)
      - Budget Proposal, undated (Box 4, Folder 273)
      - National Endowment for the Humanities: News Bulletoin, undated (Box 4, Folder 274)
      - Budgetary Records, 1974 January-June (Box 4, Folder 275)
    - Economic Status of Yale Faculty, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 276)
    - Programs in International Studies: Annual Report, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 277)
    - Yale University: Literature Programs and Curricula, undated (Box 4, Folder 278)
    - Yale University: the Literature Major and Literature X Programs, undated (Box 4, Folder 279)
    - A Proposal for Graduate Study in the Humanities: William F. May, undated (Box 4, Folder 280)
    - Research Grant, Fellowship, and Foundation Information, undated (Box 5, Folder 281)
    - Rockefeller Foundation: General Correspondence and Information, undated (Box 5, Folder 282)
    - Stanford University: Programs in the Humanities, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 283)
    - Structure of Knowledge course: Timothy Dwight College, undated (Box 5, Folder 284)
    - Summer Term Curriculum, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 285)
    - Yale Bicentennial Coordination Committee, 1974-1976 (Box 5, Folder 286)
    - Yale College: standing committees, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 287)
    - Yale Law School: Proposal to the National Endowment for the Humanities, undated (Box 5, Folder 288)
    - G. Hartman, undated (Box 5, Folder 289)
    - Miller/Hartman Report on Special Projects: NEH, undated (Box 5, Folder 290)
    - Provostial Advisory Committee Meeting, undated (Box 5, Folder 291)
    - Foreign Language Reports and Programs, undated (Box 5, Folder 292)
    - Faculty Lists: Members of Faculty of Arts for Academic year, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 293)
    - Culler Report, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 294)
    - The Fourth International Congress on The Enlightenment, Jul 1975, at Yale University (Georges May) (Box 5, Folder 295)
    - Literature and Psychology Graduate Program, SUNY Buffalo (Norman N. Holland), undated (Box 5, Folder 296)
    - Literature Major, Governing Board Minutes of meeting, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 297)
    - National Humanities Institute, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 298)
    - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies: Mellon Fellows, undated (Box 5, Folder 299)
- Committee records, 1978-1982; Accession 1989-A-003
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2018.
  - Afro-American Studies, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Studies, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Budget, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Classics, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Comparative Literature, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Concilium, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - English Department, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - French Department, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - German Department, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - History Department, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - History of Art Department, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Italian, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Language Teaching, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Linguistics, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Mid-East Materials, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Minutes of Meetings, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Music, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Near Eastern Languages, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Procedures, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Provostial Correspondence, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Provostial General File, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Religious Studies, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Senior Appointments Committee Meetings, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Slavics, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Statistical Data, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Afro-American Studies, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - American Studies, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Anthropology, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Classics, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Comparative Literature, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - East Asian Languages & Literatures, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - English, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Expository Writing, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Film Studies, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - French, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - German, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - History, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - History of Art, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Italian, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Judaic Studies, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Linguistics, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Medieval Studies, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 43)